Rohail Mustafa Syed

Email: rmsyed@umich.edu, Phone: (734)-474-5198

OBJECTIVES

To advance the cause of learning and expand the realm of knowledge through research and collaboration with visionaries and thought leaders as part of a world class team. Carry out projects and studies which contribute towards understanding, investigating, designing and developing of viable solutions to interesting and challenging questions. To create market and social value through innovation and entrepreneurship!

EDUCATION

	OCATION			
•	PhD Information (In-Progress) CGPA: 3.716/4.00	2014-Present		
	School of Information			
	University of Michigan, Ann Arbor			
•	BSc Engineering	2010-2014		
	School of Electrical Engineering and Computer Science (SEECS),			
	National University of Sciences and Technology (NUST), Islamabad			
•	A-Levels (Edexcel International, UK)	2010		
W	ORKSHOPS & ONLINE COURSES			
•	Conducted IEEE Flash Workshop for Engineering Students at NUST	2011		
	Participant IEEE Android Development Workshop	2011		
•	Machine Learning Online Course, Stanford University, USA	2011		
	•			
•	Introduction to Databases Online Course, Stanford University, USA	2011		
WORK EXPERIENCE & ACCIOTANTOLIE				
VV	ORK EXPERIENCE & ASSISTANTSHIP	00445		
•	Graduate Student Research Assistant (GSRA) at University of Michigan	2014-Present		
•	Teaching Assistant (TA) for course of Engineering Economics at NUST	2012		
•	Summer Internship on Android Budget Management Project at NUST	2012		
•	Paid Research Internship – Android Based Home Automation	2012		
	Project sponsored by National Radio and Telecom Corporation (NRTC)			
•	Research Internship – iTeach,uLearn innovative Teaching, universal Learning Project	2013		
	Project sponsored by National Foundation for Resource Development (NFRD)			

RESEARCH/SEMESTER PROJECTS

•	Real-time Intrinsically Diverse Search engine (ongoing)	2014-Present
•	Autonomous Landmine Detection and Mapping System	2014
•	Accelerometer-based Virtual Archery	2013
•	Android Home Automation System	2012
•	Online Crime Reporting System	2012
•	Cryptographic Encryption Algorithm Implementation	2010
•	Fast Food Order and Delivery System	2007

COMPUTER SKILLS

- Object-Oriented Programming (OOP)
 - o C++, Java, Python
- Web Development (Client-side)
 - o HTML5, CSS3, Javascript, JQuery, Flash
- Web Development (Server-side)
 - o PHP, MySQL, SQLite
- Mobile Development
 - Android
- Other Programming
 - o C, Visual Basic, Matlab, Octave
- Hardware Development
 - o Assembly Code, Embedded C

ACHIEVEMENTS

•	President's Gold Medal for Academics at NUST Won 3 rd place award for best Final Year Project Academic Merit Scholarship Stanford Extended Education Program Advanced 2011 Track Courses IEEE-SEECS Chapter Webmaster at NUST IEEE-SEECS Chapter Member Executive Committee at NUST Certified IBM DB2 Academic Associate Chief Minister Academic Achievement Award	2014 2014 2010-2014 2011 2011 2012 2012
•	Chief Minister Academic Achievement Award	2013

PROFESSIONAL INTERESTS

- Information Retrieval
- Human-Computer Interaction
- Artificial Intelligence, Data Mining & Pattern Recognition